Marco Tessarin

Full Stack Engineer

- ▲ Download PDF
- marcotessarindev@gmail.com
- github.com/fury90723
- in linkedin.com/in/marco-tessarin-86b925195

Profile

I'm a full stack engineer with experience developing complex web applications comprehensive of front-end, back-end and deployment. I specialise in JavaScript, working in agile environments and leveraging modern technologies like React.js, Redux, Node.js. I also don't mind to work with Java Spring in which I am experienced.

Lately I have been developing the front-end of an IOT system which empower the users through FIWARE, a framework for smart solutions.

Skills

- JavaScript/ES6
- HTML5, CSS
- React, Redux
- jQuery / Bootstrap
- Responsive Design
- Node.js / Express
- Java 8+
- Spring Boot
- Strapi
- jUnit
- Docker
- Kubernetes
- Helm
- RabbitMQ
- Python / Raspberry PI

Experience

AMG Solution - Tokyo, JP Full Stack Engineer (Consultant)

April 2019 - Now

- Intermediate Developer position.
- Created an IOT platform from the ground up. Implementing the microservice architecture at scale, I take proud of having created the main front-end all by myself.
- React.js & Material Design were the bread and butter of my everyday coding routine.
- I also contributed to the back-end Open Api built on Node.js with the design and coding for some of the main routes.
- Leveraged my knowledge of Docker & AWS, helping the team on the deploying phase.
- Used Databases were mostly MongoDB and Postgres but I also implemented APIs with Elastic Search to handle large amounts of data when needed.
- Mentored a Junior Developer who had never worked with microservices. Helping with Docker

and the basics of Kubernetes.

- Wrote scripts in Python that allowed a Raspberry Pi IOT enabled with sensors to be connected to our web application.
- During this time I also built a prototype React Native app for IOS & Android.

株式会社STA

Front & Back End Engineer(Consultant)

November 2017 - April 2019

- Junior Engineer position.
- Mostly Back-end development in Java Spring.
- Created an administration system for a VPP (virtual power plant), contributing with Java Spring(mostly JPA), junit and writing JSP pages with the help of Bootstrap & jQuery.
- Learned and practiced testing with the jUnit framework and mockito.
- Built a big administration SMS batch in Spring, MySQL for a famous Japanese company. Learned and implemented Design Patterns. Monolithic Architecture.
- The Databases I mostly used during this period were Postgres and MySQL
- Every evening after work I would study React.js and Node.js that served me very well for future work experiences and that I really linkedin to work with. (online courses: Scrimba: React full course (35 hrs) Udemy: React and Node courses, various (120hrs) Egghead.io: various courses (15 hrs) Udemy: React Native course for mobile apps (30hrs))
- Only Japanese Environment.

Education

Bootcamp: Web Develpment

Heatwave Programming School - Shinjuku, Tokyo, JP

Mar 2017 - Nov 2017

- Focused on learning Web Development. Java was the main taught language for the programming basics and HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, JSP, Java(Servlet) were the technologies used to build web applications.
- I learned a lot of basics during that time that I still use today on my day to day job.
- I have got 3 working offers during this time according to my coding skills that I refused because I wanted to really learn the basics and be effective on my future workplaces.

Faculty of Foreign Languages: Japanese / English Torino University - Torino, IT

Oct 2010 - Sep 2012

- Focused on Japanese and English studies.
- Completed Computer Science course for extra credits. Basics of Algorithms.
- Dropped out after two years for private reasons.